A Guide to the Papers of Ralph Eisenberg, 1960-1972
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of Ralph Eisenberg 1960-1972
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
12774-a
This collection consists of ca. 2,000 items (6.5 Hollinger boxes ca. 2.7 linear shelf feet).
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
The collection was given to the library by the Center for Public Services on September 14, 1989 and by Mrs. Phyllis Eisenberg of Charlottesville, Virginia, on July 26, 1990.
Scope and Content Information
The papers consist of ca. 2,000 items (6.5 Hollinger boxes ca. 2.7 linear shelf feet), and dates approximately from 1960-1972. This collection is comprised of Ralph Eisenberg's research files, newspaper clippings, correspondence, typescripts of his articles and those of his colleagues, and published journals and articles, most concerning his work on legislative reapportionment.
Organization
The additional papers of Ralph Eisenberg are comprised of two accessions interfiled and are arranged alphabetically within three series: I. State Apportionments; II. General Files; and, III. Clippings.
Contents List
- Series I: State Apportionments
  - Alabama 1961 (Box 1)
  - Alaska n.d. (Box 1)
  - Arizona 1961 (Box 1)
  - Arkansas 1961 (Box 1)
  - California 1960 (Box 1)
  - Colorado 1961 (Box 1)
  - Connecticut 1961 (Box 1)
  - Delaware n.d. (Box 1)
  - Florida 1960 (Box 1)
  - Georgia 1961 (Box 1)
  - Hawaii 1961 (Box 1)
  - Idaho 1960 (Box 1)
  - Illinois 1960-1961 (Box 1)
  - Indiana 1960-1961 (Box 1)
  - Iowa 1961 (Box 1)
  - Kansas 1961 (Box 1)
  - Kentucky 1960 (Box 2)
  - Louisiana 1961 (Box 2)
  - Maine 1961 (Box 2)
  - Maryland 1961 (Box 2)
  - Massachusetts 1961 (Box 2)
  - Michigan 1961 (Box 2)
  - Minnesota 1961 (Box 2)
  - Mississippi n.d. (Box 2)
  - Missouri 1961 (Box 2)
  - Montana 1961 (Box 2)
  - Nebraska n.d. (Box 2)
  - Nevada 1961 (Box 2)
  - New Hampshire 1961 (Box 2)
  - New Jersey n.d. (Box 2)
  - New Mexico 1961 (Box 2)
  - New York 1960-1961 (Box 2)
  - North Carolina 1961 (Box 3)
  - North Dakota 1960 (Box 3)
  - Ohio 1961 (Box 3)
  - Oklahoma 1961 (Box 3)
  - Oregon 1961 (Box 3)
  - Pennsylvania 1961 (Box 3)
  - Rhode Island 1961 (Box 3)
  - South Carolina 1961 (Box 3)
  - South Dakota 1961 (Box 3)
  - Tennessee n.d. (Box 3)
  - Texas 1961 (Box 3)
  - Utah 1961 (Box 3)
  - Vermont 1960 (Box 3)
  - Virginia n.d. (Box 3)
  - Washington 1961 (Box 3)
  - West Virginia n.d. (Box 3)
  - Wisconsin 1961 (Box 3)
  - Wyoming n.d. (Box 3)
- Series II: General Files
  - Civil Action No. 2604 - Disposition of Ralph Eisenberg 1962 (Box 4)
  - Correspondence, Vita, R/T Booklet [1968-1969] (Box 4)
  - Course Syllabi and Examinations [1968-1971] (Box 4)
  - Department of Government and Foreign Affairs Reports and Memoranda [1964-1977] (Box 4)
  - Eisenberg Papers/Reports [1966-1971], 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Illinois House Bill 1964 (Box 4)
  - Institute of Government - Miscellaneous 1966-1971 (Box 4)
  - Michigan Apportionment Case 1964 (Box 5)
  - Miscellaneous n.d. (Box 5)
  - National Civic Review 1962 (Box 5)
  - The 100-Year Flood [1970] (Box 5)
  - [Pattern of Mexican Politics] n.d. (Box 5)
  - Phase IV Worksheets 1962 (Box 5)
  - Project Information n.d. (Box 5)
  - Reapportionment: One Man, One Vote - Misc. Typescripts 1961-1972, 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Training Data n.d. (Box 5)
- Series III: Clippings
  - Apportionment Clippings 1961-1963, 3 folders (Box 6)
  - National Apportionment 1963-1964, 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Virginia Election Clippings 1961 (Box 6)
  - Virginia Legislative Apportionment Case 1962-1963 (Box 6)
  - Virginia Politics 1963-1964, 2 folders (Box 7)
  - Virginia Politics - Elections Clippings 1963 (Box 7)
  - Virginia Poll Tax 1963-1964 (Box 7)
  - Virginia Poll Tax - Special Session Clippings 1963 (Box 7)